

#### **BIKASH SHARMA**

Full Stack Developer

Helsinki, Finland bikashxsharma@gmail.com

+358 440347283

- **(7)** /bikashxsharma
- in /in/bikashxsharma
- bikashxsharma.github.io

## Skills

#### Front-end

- · HTML, CSS, SASS
- · JavaScript & TypeScript
- Javao
- ReactVue.js
- Context, Redux, Vuex

#### Back-end & DevOps

- · Node.js & TypeScript
- · Express
- · SQL, MongoDB
- · Google Cloud
- · Docker
- · Kubernetes

#### UX/UI

- · User Research
- · User Journey
- · Wireframe
- · Prototype
- · Mockups

## Additional

- Socket.ioWordPress
- · PHP
- · Python
- · Git

## Tools

- · Figma · Adobe suite
- · |ira
- · Intercom
- · Github
- PostmanLens

## English - FluentFinnish - Intermediate

Languages

- Nepali NativeHindi Advanced

I'm a Helsinki-based full-stack developer focused on writing code that makes an impact on users. I have also gained experience as a consultant, product designer, and digital marketer. My experience as a UX designer and startup co-founder has opened the ability to understand both the business side as well as the users' side of any project. Always willing to learn more.

## Experience

#### Lead Product Developer

Wonsta Oy | Helsinki, Finland | 05.2021 - present

Lead the product development of Google Cloud-based WordPress hosting and management platform from day one. Engaged in UX/UI design, decisions as well as the business side of the product.

- · Full-phase front-end in Vue.js.
- Back-end with Node, express, TypeScript and Cloud SQL.
- · Integrated payment method with Stripe.
- of the project.

  Design the arhitecture of both front-end and back-end

· Contributed to Google cloud and the kubernetes side

- as well as took part in planning and implementing the need of WordPress hosting using GKE and other Google Cloud APIs.Actively took part in the product planning, user
- research, partnership and development roadmaps.

  Planned, developed and managed analytics, events
- and event driven email automation using Intercom.

## Software Developer

Great Slogan Oy | Helsinki, Finland | 10.2020 - 05.2021

Wonsta. Additionally worked on numerous WordPress projects.

Initiated the spin-off app from the scratch both front-

Worked on spin-off product which later continued as

- end and back-end.
- Worked on several WordPress projects from the design to finish with custom build themes.
  Lead and built the front-end of real-time order

# Web Developer, UX/UI designer & Co-founder Velkko Oy | Helsinki, Finland | 10.2016 - 10.2020

Co-founded a web design agency with a friend. Helped

management application of a restaurant in React.

.....

small businesses to improve their online presence.

· UX/UI design.

- · Maintained hosting, domain names, and other tech
- requirements.

  Involved in digital marketing for both Velkko and its
- clients with Facebook, Instagram, and Google Ads.Followed project management practices and led multiple projects.
- Product Designer, Digital marketer & Co-founder

Doctual Oy | Helsinki, Finland | 01.2017 - 11.2018

Co-founded a legal-tech platform to create legal documents online, review and do the online signature.

needs, and user testing and gathered user feedback.Developed product road map and collaborated with technical team and stakeholders for product

· Conducted user research to understand the product

- development and planning.Developed wireframes and low-fidelity prototypes as well as high-fidelity and clickable prototypes.
- Prepared software test cases for testing.Developed and implemented digital customer acquisition campaigns.

Optimized landing pages, analytics, events, and page

- contents for more effective SEO.
- Developed brand guidelines.Represented the Doctual during various startup events.

# Education ——

#### M.B.A in Business Technology

Haaga-Helia University of Applied Sciences

Helsinki, Finland | 01.2020 - Present

## B.Eng. in Media Engineering

Metropolia University of Applied Sciences

Espoo, Finland | 08.2012 - 05.2016

B.Eng. in Information Technology

Turku University of Applied Sciences

Turku, Finland | 08.2009 - 09.2013 (Incomplete)